Alrighty. So in this video, I'm going to be going over the installation of Git and Visual
Studio Code on Windows. So the first thing we're going to do is we're going to open
up our browser and we're going to type in git for windows.org. You can see it's popping
up here. And on this page, we're simply going to click on the download button. And we're
going to wait for this to finish downloading. And then we're going to go ahead and open up
the installer. Okay, so you can see that we have our installer open. We do want to install
this. Yes. We can minimize this for now. And you'll see that we have our installation
here. We're just going to click next. You can change the folder that it's going to install
to. But for me, this is fine. And I click next. And one thing to note just to make sure
it's checked is we have a Windows Explorer integration. And it has a checkbox for open Git
Bash here, open Git GUI here. So I actually find this very useful. I'll explain why in
a few minutes, but just make sure that this is checked here. Then we're going to click
next, next again. And now we have come to the question of which editor would we like
Git to use? So you can see in the dropdown, there's a few different choices here. And
we actually want to use Visual Studio code as gets default editor. So we're going to click
on that. And you can see that the next button here is grayed out. That's because we haven't
yet installed Visual Studio code. But we can do that by simply clicking on this link here.
And we want to open this in Edge. And so we're at the Visual Studio code website. And we're
going to go ahead and click download for Windows. And this should be downloading here. Yep.
And we're going to wait for it to finish. And then we're actually going to run the Visual
Studio code setup first before we finish our Git setup. So we're going to go ahead and
open this file now. Minimize the browser. Okay. And we're going to accept this agreement. Again,
you can choose which folder it's going to install in for me. That's fine. Next. And we're
going to call it Visual Studio code and start menu. Sure. And again, there's a few things
that you can check here. And they're related to the Windows Explorer file context menu.
And the directory menu. So basically it adds an option to open with code. I'll show you
what that means in a moment. And also, I usually like to check register code as the editor
for supported file types. So open up anything that is code related within Visual Studio
code automatically. We'll associate all of those file types. And I'm going to go ahead
and create a desktop icon here as well. Then I'm going to click next and install.
Okay. Now that the setup is complete, I'm not going to launch Visual Studio code quite
yet. But I'm going to click on finish. And now it's still great out. The next button
here on our Git setup. So I'm just going to hit the back button first. Then I'm going
to click next. And you can see now that I've installed Visual Studio code, I can now click
this next button for the rest of these settings. I'm just going to go with the defaults.
So I'm just going to keep clicking next. Okay. And then that is going to finish our setup
for Git on Windows here. Okay. Great. That's finished as well. We don't need to view the
release notes. So we're just going to uncheck that and click on finish. Okay. Great. So we've
installed Git on Windows as well as Visual Studio code. Now I want to show you a few things
about the context menu. So for me personally, I am normally developing on Windows. I work
with Windows at work. And I worked with Windows when I was learning development, though
I am going to be recording the course on a Mac. Most of the rest of what I'm going to talk
about is going to apply throughout the rest of the course. However, what I'm about to show
you doesn't quite work the same way on Mac. So this is unique to Windows. So if I right
click I have a code folder here. You'll see that I have a few different options in the context
menu. So that was what I was mentioning in both setups. So what this allows me to do.
If I click open Git Bash here, it allows me to actually open a terminal within this file
path. So it's a quick and easy way to get directly to this location on my computer instead
of having to use commands to actually get to this specific file path. This can be useful
for a whole host of things. But for me personally, I always found it useful when I was trying
to create a new Angular app. Because to do that, you just need to type ng new and then
the app name. And then it will automatically create an Angular project within that folder,
just something to consider in the future. And the other cool thing is if I right click
on this and I click open with code, this will allow me to automatically open this folder
up in Visual Studio code. So you can see that right away, I am in this project and I can
go ahead and click on the code within the project. So this is very useful. For Windows,
I'm not going to be able to show off either feature because I'm going to record the rest of
the course on Mac. But if you are using Windows, it is very handy to be able to right click
and open with code or to open a Git Bash terminal in any folder location. All right. So that's it
for our Windows setup. Everything else we're going to discuss for the rest of the course,
it will apply to both Windows and Mac related to Visual Studio code and everything like that.
That is the great thing about it is that it works the same way regardless of the platform
that you are using it on. All right. That's it for this one. Bye for now.